screencast-o-matic.com 2019-06-14

# Screencast-O-Matic Privacy Policy | Screen Recorder & Video Editor | Screencast-O-Matic

### **1\. What information do we collect?**

**Information You Provide.   **We collect and use the following information to provide, improve, promote, and protect our Services and to offer effective advertising, which helps us keep many of our Services free:

  * **Account Data**. We may ask you to provide, and if provided will associate with your account, information like your name, email address, phone number, payment info, and physical address. Some of our services let you access your accounts and your information with other service providers. You can modify your account information while logged in by clicking on your username in the global navigation bar at the top of the screen. When you subscribe to any of our paid Services using a credit or debit card, our third party payment provider will collect payment and billing information in order to complete the transaction. Screencast-O-Matic does not store or otherwise use this information.
  * **Contacts and address book information.**  When you share your User Content via email or invite others to join Screencast-O-Matic you will need to provide us with email addresses for each person that you wish to send Your Content or to invite to join Screencast-O-Matic. We use this information to send your invitation but do not use these emails for any other purpose.
  * **Your Content.**  When you use our Services to upload content you generate (“Your Content”), we store, process and transmit Your Content and related information (for example, title and description). Users have the option to password protect their screencasts from public viewing. If you do not select password protection, Your Content may be available to and viewable by other users and by the public. We also collect usage statistics from our Software, which could include metadata such as the date and time the content was created and posted, the title of the content, viewing history, etc..

**Information about your use of the Services.**  Like most online services, we automatically collect certain types of usage information when you visit our Service, read our emails or otherwise engage with us. This information is typically collected through a variety of tracking technologies, including cookies, web beacons, Locally Stored Objects (LSOs such as Flash or HTML5), log files, and similar technology (collectively, “tracking technologies”), and we may use third party providers to collect this information on our behalf.

  * **Email Communications:**  We may receive a confirmation when you open an email from us and when you click a link in an email. We use this confirmation to improve our Services, including customer service. We may use a third party service provider to handle email communications.
  * **Usage and device information:**  We collect information from and about the devices you use to access the Services. This includes things like IP addresses, a unique device identifier, the type of browser and device you use, operating system, location, date and timestamp of your transactions, the computer peripherals you use such as webcam, the web page you visited before coming to our sites, and identifiers associated with your devices. Your devices (depending on their settings) may also transmit location information to the Services or we may be able to approximate a device’s location by analyzing other information, like an IP address. We may use this usage- and device-related information in order to provide and improve the Services.
  * **Analytics and behavioural information**. We may collect analytics data, or use third-party analytics tools such as Google Analytics, to help us measure traffic, user events, and usage trends for the Service and to understand more about the demographics of our users. We may also track analytics data and viewing activity of content created by or hosted on the Service. You can learn more about Google’s practices at <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners>. and view its currently available opt-out options at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. We may also work with third party partners to employ technologies, including the application of statistical modeling tools, which permit us to recognize and contact you across multiple devices.
  * You can find out more about our use of cookies and similar technologies in  **our Cookie Policy**.

**Legal basis for processing in the EU   **

In the EU, the purposes for which we process your personal data are:

  * where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you for the Service;
  * where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests such as (i) to contact you and respond to your requests and enquiries; (ii) for business administration, including statistical analysis; (iii) to provide the Service to you; and (iv) for fraud prevention and detection; and
  * where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation in the EU.

We may also process your personal data on the basis of your freely given, specific, informed and unambiguous consent. You should be aware that you are entitled under the GDPR to withdraw your consent where that has been given, at any time.  If you do this and we have no alternative lawful reason to process your personal data, this may affect our ability to provide you with rights to use the Service.

Please contact us at [mailto:privacy@screencast-o-matic.com](mailto:privacy@screencast-o-matic.com) if you need details about the specific legal basis we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one legal basis has been set out.

### **2.  ** **Information Sharing**

We may share information as needed to provide the Service or with your consent or permission. but we will not sell or rent your information to 3rd parties for their direct marketing purposes. We may also share personal information in the circumstances described below: as discussed below.

  * **Third-party vendors, consultants and other service providers working for Screencast-O-Matic**. Screencast-O-Matic uses certain trusted third parties to help us provide, improve, protect, and promote our Services. These third parties will access your personal information only to perform tasks on our behalf and in compliance with this Privacy Policy. You can see our list of third party vendors here.
  * **Third-Party Applications**. Screencast-O-Matic may share your Information with a third party application with your consent, for example when you choose to access our Services through such an application. We are not responsible for what those parties do with your information, so you should make sure you trust the application and that it has a privacy policy acceptable to you.  Examples of third party applications include a Learning Management System or authentication service.
  * We may disclose your information to third parties, including government officials, if we determine that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with the law; (b) protect any person from death or serious bodily injury; (c) prevent fraud or abuse of Screencast-O-Matic or our users; o (d) protect Screencast-o-matic’s property rights or safety; (e) enforce our TOS, including the investigation of potential violations thereof; and (f) detect, prevent or otherwise address criminal, security or technical issues .
  * We may share your personal information with other parties in connection with any company transaction, such as a merger, sale of all or a portion of company assets or shares, reorganization, financing, change of control or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company or third party or in the event of bankruptcy or related or similar proceedings
  * We may also provide aggregated, non-personal information to third parties for any legal purposes whatsoever.

### **3.  ** **Your Content on the Service**

**User Content** :  Personal information that you voluntarily disclose in content you create (i.e. videos, screenshots, documents, metadata, etc.) as part of the Services may be viewed by other users and the public on the Service, and we do not control how these third parties may use, save, and share your Content.  You are responsible for the security and management of any personal information contained in Your Content, and for ensuring you have all necessary rights and permissions to disclose personal information in your Content.  We reserve the right, but not the obligation, to remove and/or delete any Content that we believe contains personal information that infringes on the privacy rights of any individual or for any other reason, at our discretion.

**Chat Rooms and Forums** : The Services may now or in the future include web logs (i.e., blogs), chat rooms, post-it boards, forums, message boards, and/or news groups. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. You should exercise caution before disclosing your personal information via these public venues, which you do at your own risk. Screencast-O-Matic cannot safeguard the privacy of personal information that is disclosed online in this manner.

### **4.  ** **Third party tracking and online advertising**

Our ability to provide free content and services depends on advertising.

We participate in interest-based advertising and use third party advertising companies to serve you targeted advertisements based on your browsing history.  We may share, or we may permit third party online advertising networks, social media companies and other third party services, to collect, information about your use of our Service so that they may play or display ads on our Service, including on pages that we host for viewing your uploaded content, on other devices you may use, and on other websites, apps or services, including on Facebook.  These third parties may collect information such as click stream information, browser type, time and date you visited the site, mobile device identifiers, app usage, and/or precise geolocation data and other information. We and our third party partners use this information to make the advertisements you see online more relevant to your interests, as well as to provide advertising-related services such as reporting, attribution, analytics and market research.

We may also utilize certain forms of display advertising and other advanced features through Google Universal Analytics, such as Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, the DoubleClick Campaign Manager Integration, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. These features enable us to use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the Doubleclick advertising cookie) or other third party cookies together to inform, optimize, and display ads based on your past visits to the Services. You may control your advertising preferences or opt-out of certain Google advertising products by visiting the Google Ads Preferences Manager, currently available at [https://google.com/ads/preferences](https://google.com/ads/preferences%20) or by vising NAI’s online resources at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>.

To learn about interest-based advertising and how you may be able to opt-out of some of this advertising, you may wish to visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s online resources, at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>, and/or the DAA’s resources at [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).  You may also manage certain advertising cookies by visiting the EU-based Your Online Choices at [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

Please note that opting-out of receiving interest-based advertising through the NAI, DAA or Your Online Choices online resources will only opt-out a user from receiving interest-based ads on that specific browser or device, but you may still receive interest-based ads on your other devices. You must perform the opt-out on each browser or device you use.

Some of these opt-outs may not be effective unless your browser is set to accept cookies. If you delete cookies, change your browser settings, switch browsers or computers, or use another operating system, you will need to opt-out again.

You may also be able to limit interest-based advertising through the settings on your mobile device by selecting “limit ad tracking” (iOS) or “opt-out of interest based ads” (Android).  You may also be able to opt-out of some—but not all—interest-based ads served by mobile ad networks by visiting <http://youradchoices.com/appchoices> and downloading the mobile AppChoices app.

### **5.  ** **Children’s Privacy**

Screencast-O-Matic complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) and recognizes the privacy interests of children. Screencast-O-Matic does not direct its Services to children under 13 or knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. In the EU, Screencast-O-Matic is not intended to be used by children under the age of 16 and will not knowingly process personal information of a child under 16 on the grounds of consent.

Educators may use the Screencast-O-Matic Service in the classroom for the benefit of students, including those under the age of 13. Educators may permit students under 13 to use the Service for educational purposes only if they have the authority to provide such consent on the parent’s behalf, as permitted by COPPA.  We strongly recommend that Educators do not permit or require children under 13 to provide personal information to our Service. Instead, you can use our free recording tools or one of our Team Plans without providing any personal information and you can host your Content on your School’s platform and systems so that students can view such content on School-provided systems. See Section 7: Educational Use and Student Data below to learn more.

If we discover we have received any personal information from a child under the age of 13 in violation of this Policy, we will take reasonable steps to delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe we have any information from or about anyone under the age of 13, please contact us at [privacy@screencast-o-matic.com](mailto:privacy@screencast-o-matic.com).

### **6.  ** **Educational Use and Student Data**

Screencast-O-Matic may be used by schools, school districts, or educators (collectively, “Schools”) and their Students in an educational setting. We understand that personal information relating to students may include personal information from “educational records” as defined by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”), 20 U.S.C. § 1232(g) (“Student Data”) and may be protected by other data privacy laws, including COPPA and relevant state laws.

The most privacy-protective manner Schools may use our Service is to not permit or require students to provide  _ _any__  personal information to the Service. Instead, we recommend using our free recording or one of our Team Plans without providing any personal information relating to students, and the School can host Content on the School’s own platform so that students can view Content on School-provided systems and avoid providing any personally identifiable student information to Screencast-O-Matic. Our Service complies with the requirements of FERPA, COPPA and other applicable student privacy laws by requiring (indeed, by prohibiting) students and School from providing personal information related to students to the Service.

Please note, Educators are solely responsible for assuring compliance with FERPA, COPPA and other privacy laws which may be applicable to the personal information of non-users, including, potentially, K12 students, that may be contained in the Content uploaded to the Service.

### **7.  ** **Information Protection**

**Security.** Screencast-O-Matic maintains reasonable security measures to help protect your information from loss, destruction, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure. These security measures can include, but are not limited to, password protection, need-based access, firewall and encryption, employee training, and other such mechanisms. Our security team periodically reviews our information storage and security practices and updates our policies and practices as needed to address changing technologies and known threats.   These measures and technologies help ensure that your data is safe, secure, and only available to you and to those you provided authorized access. However, no data transmission over the Internet or information storage technology can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

**Storage.  **To provide you with the Services, we may store, process and transmit information in locations around the world – including those outside your country. Information may also be stored locally on the devices you use to access the Services.

Screencast-O-Matic is hosted in the United States. If you are a user accessing Screencast-O-Matic from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of Screencast-O-Matic, which is governed by U.S. law, this Privacy Policy, and Screencast-O-Matic’s Terms of Service, you are transferring your personal information to the United States

**Other Websites:**  When using the Services, you may be directed to other third party websites that are beyond our control. These other websites may use cookies and pixel tags, collect data, or solicit personal information. Screencast-O-Matic has no control over such third party websites, nor over how they collect, distribute or otherwise use your personal information or how they safeguard and secure your personal information. Screencast-O-Matic is not responsible or liable for the conduct, policies or actions of the owners of such third party websites or the content displayed on these websites. Any third party websites are linked to the Services only for your convenience and you access them at your own risk.

### **8.  ** **Your choices regarding your information.**

You may edit your account information at any time by signing into your account.

**Marketing Communications:**  If you do not wish to receive marketing emails, you can click the “unsubscribe” button on promotional email communications.

**Data Retention.**  We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide the Service and for our internal business purposes, which may extend beyond the termination or cancellation of your subscription or user account, or until we receive a deletion request. Please contact us at privacy@screencast-o-matic.com if you wish to delete your account or content permanently from our systems. Please be aware that we will not be able to delete any content you have shared with others or posted to third-party services.

**Deleting or Anonymizing Your Content.  **If you are under 18 years of age, you may request that the personal information contained in Content that you posted to the Services be deleted or anonymized such that your personal information will not be identifiable publicly on our Services by contacting us at privacy@screencast-o-matic.com. While we will use all commercially reasonable efforts to delete or anonymize your User Content upon request, please be aware that due to the social nature of our Services, you may not be able to completely remove all of your personally identifiable User Content if, for example, that content has been stored, republished, or reposted by another user or a third party. We may also maintain your information in identifiable form for our internal use, even if your personal data is no longer visible to the public on our Services.

### **9.  ** **The General Data Protection Regulation**

**EU users’ specific rights and choices.   **If you are located in the EU or Switzerland, you have the following rights in respect of your personal data that we hold:

  * **Right of access**. The right to obtain access to your personal data;
  * **Right to rectification.**  The right to obtain rectification of your personal data without undue delay where that personal data is inaccurate or incomplete;
  * **Right to erasure**. The right to obtain the erasure of your personal data without undue delay in certain circumstances, such as where the personal data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or processed;
  * **Right to restriction.**  The right to obtain the restriction of the processing undertaken by us on your personal data in certain circumstances, such as where the accuracy of the personal data is contested by you, for a period enabling us to verify the accuracy of that personal data;
  * **Right to portability.**  The right to portability allows you to move, copy or transfer personal data easily from one organization to another; and
  * **Right to object**. You have a right to object to processing based on legitimate interests and direct marketing.

If you wish to exercise one of these rights, please contact us using the contact details at the end of this Privacy Policy.

You also have the right to  **lodge a complaint**  to your local data protection authority. Further information about how to contact your local data protection authority is available at <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>.

**EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield**

Screencast-O-Matic complies with the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union member countries (including Lichtenstein, Norway & Iceland) and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Consistent with our commitment to protect personal information about individuals in the European Union , Screencast-O-Matic has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, and Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability (the “Privacy Shield Principles” or the “Principles”). Screencast-O-Matic’s EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Certification also extends to personal information that we receive directly through the Services. More information on the EU-U.S. and Swiss Privacy Shield and Screencast-O-Matic’s scope of participation in the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework is available at http://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome.

If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.

For more information regarding Screencast-O-Matic’s compliance with the U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Privacy Shield Principles, please see our Privacy Shield Privacy Statement.

### **10.  ** **Changes to this Policy**

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time, with or without notice to you, by posting a copy of the most current version on our website and/or making it available through the Services. You are responsible for reviewing the Privacy Policy, and you will be deemed to have agreed to any modification or amendment to the Privacy Policy by your decision to continue to use or access the Services after the date on which the revised Privacy Policy is posted or made available through the Services.

### **Screencast-O-Matic Cookie Policy**

This cookies policy applies when using the Screencast-O-Matic websites, services and products (collectively, our “Service”).

We use cookies and similar technologies to distinguish you from other visitors and users of the Service. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse the Service and also allows us to improve the Service.

**Information automatically collected through cookies and other technologies**

Cookies are small data files that are placed on Your computer or mobile device when You visit a website or use the Services.  Cookies are widely used by website owners in order to make their websites and services work, or to work more efficiently, as well as to provide reporting information.

Cookies set by the website owner (in this case, Screencast-O-Matic) are called “first party cookies”.  Cookies set by parties other than the website owner are called “third party cookies”.  Third party cookies enable third party features or functionality to be provided on or through the website (e.g. like advertising, interactive content and analytics).  The parties that set these third party cookies can recognize Your computer both when it visits the website in question or uses the Services and also when it visits certain other websites.

We use technologies like cookies, web beacons, and pixel tags to provide, improve, protect and promote our Services. For example, Cookies help us with things like remembering your username for your next visit, understanding how you are interacting with our Services, and improving them based on that information.

We use first party and third-party cookies for several reasons. Some cookies are required for technical reasons in order for Our Services to operate, and We refer to these as “essential” or “strictly necessary” cookies. Other cookies also enable Us to track and target the interests of Our users to enhance the experience on Our Services.   Third parties serve cookies through Our Services for advertising, analytics and other purposes such as performance and functionality.  This is described in more detail below.

Cookies are Served Through Our Services:

**WHO SERVES THESE COOKIES***

**Essential website cookies**

These cookies are strictly necessary to provide You with services available through Our Services and to use some of their features, such as the ability to sign in and access to secure areas

**Performance and functionality cookies**

These cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help Us understand how Our Services are being used or how effective Our marketing campaigns are, or to help Us customize Our Services for You.

These cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help Us understand how Our Services are being used or how effective Our marketing campaigns are, or to help Us customize Our Services for You.

**Analytics or customization cookies.**

These cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help Us understand how Our Services are being used or how effective Our marketing campaigns are, or to help Us customize Our Services for You.

Google Analytics

Google Tag Manager

Amplitude Analytics

These cookies are used to make advertising messages more relevant to You.  They perform functions like preventing the same ad from continuously reappearing to the same user, ensuring that ads are properly displayed for advertisers, and in some cases selecting advertisements that are based on Your interests.

**Social networking cookies.**

These cookies are used to enable You to share pages and content that You find interesting on Our Website through third party social networking and other websites.  These cookies may also be used for advertising purposes too.

_*These providers and third parties are subject to change over time. We will do our best to keep this list current._

The cookies we use are designed to help you get the most from the Service but if you do not wish to receive cookies, most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. Please note that if you choose to refuse cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Service. These settings will typically be found in the “options” or “preferences” menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful, otherwise you should use the “Help” option in your browser for more details.

  * [Cookie settings in Safari web](https://support.apple.com/guide/safari/manage-cookies-and-website-data-sfri11471/mac) and <https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_US>.

You may choose not to provide us with any personal information. In such event, you can still access and use many portions of the Services; however, you will not be able to access and use those portions of the Services that require your personal information.

We do not honor Do Not Track signals from your browser.

If you would like to find out more about cookies and other similar technologies, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or the Network Advertising Initiative’s online sources at [www.networkadvertising.org.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

We may update this page from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to the cookies we use or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.  Please therefore re-visit this Privacy Policy regularly to stay informed about our use of cookies and related technologies.

The date at the top of this Cookie Statement indicates when it was last updated.

### **Screencast-O-Matic Privacy Shield Statement**

Screencast-O-Matic complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries (including Lichtenstein, Norway & Iceland) and Switzerland transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield.  Screencast-O-Matic has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and data subject rights under the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.

**Purpose**

The purpose of this Screencast-O-Matic Privacy Shield Statement (“Statement”) is to outline how we comply with the Principles with respect to the personal information we collect. If you would like to obtain additional information regarding our privacy practices in connection with information collected on this website in general, please refer to our Privacy Policy. If there is any conflict between this Statement and the Privacy Policy, this Statement shall prevail.

**Scope**

This Statement applies to any personal information received by Screencast-O-Matic from the European Union (including Lichtenstein, Norway & Iceland) or Switzerland in reliance on Privacy Shield.

**Screencast-O-Matic Data Processing Activities  **

Screencast-O-Matic at times acts as a data processor or a data controller when processing personal data transferred from the EEA or Switzerland. Though the types of data Screencast-O-Matic collects and processes may vary depending on customer’s use of the Service, data we collect typically includes personal information relating to customers, billing and payments information, web browsing behavior and other information relating to a user’s device used to access the services, and other information as described in our Privacy Policy. Screencast-O-Matic processes this data to provide our business and consumer services; billing and payments; customer service and product support; communications and marketing; online advertising; analytics to inform and improve our services; and for other internal purposes.

**Principles**

  1. **Notice.**  We will provide individuals with notice of our data collection and processing practices in our Privacy Policy, describing what personal information we collect, the purpose and use of personal information, the categories of third parties with whom we may share such information (and the purposes for which we do so), the individual’s right to access such information, the choices and means through which the individual may limit the use and disclosure of personal information, and other disclosures consistent with the Notice Principle.

You can read about our data collection and processing practices in our main [Privacy Policy](https://screencast-o-matic.com/privacy).

  2. **Choice.**  We will provide an individual opt-out or opt-in choice before we share their data with third parties other than our agents and service providers, or before we use it for a purpose other than it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. To limit the use and disclosure of your personal information, please submit a written request to privacy@screencast-o-matic.com.
  3. **Onward Transfers**  (Transfer to Third Parties). Screencast-O-Matic may transfer personal information to certain third parties (as described in our [Privacy Policy](https://screencast-o-matic.com/privacy)). Where we transfer personal information to a third party, will take reasonable and appropriate steps to ensure the third-party processes personal information for limited and specified purposes and in a manner consistent with Screencast-O-Matic’s Privacy Shield obligations. Where the transfer is to a third-party agent acting on our behalf, Screencast-O-Matic may be liable if such third parties fail to meet those obligations, and we are responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

In certain situations, we may be also required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

  4. **Security.**  We take reasonable and appropriate measures to protect personal information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. We have implemented appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to help safeguard and secure personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction.
  5. **Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation.**  We will process personal information in a manner that is compatible with and relevant to the purpose for which it was collected or authorized by individuals. To the extent necessary for those purposes, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is accurate, complete, current and reliable for its intended use.
  6. **Access.**  EU and Swiss individuals have the right to reasonable access to the personal information about you that we hold. On request, we will also take reasonable steps to correct, update, amend or delete any information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate, except where the burden or expense of doing so would be disproportionate to the risks to your privacy in the case in question or where the rights of third parties would be violated. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, should direct their query to privacy@screencast-o-matic.com. If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.
  7. **Jurisdiction and Enforcement.**  As part of our participation in Privacy Shield, we are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the US Federal Trade Commission.
  8. **Lawful Requests.**  Screencast-O-Matic may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
  9. **Contact Screencast-O-Matic and Recourse.  **In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Screencast-O-Matic commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield.  EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact at privacy@screencast-o-matic.com or write to:

4244 University Way NE #45085

Seattle, Washington, 98105

In the event that you are concerned about how personal information you have provided to Screencast-O-Matic has been used, please address your inquiry or complaint first to us at the address listed above. Screencast-O-Matic takes all concerns about privacy and use of personal information very seriously, and shall endeavor to reply to you within 45 days of receiving a complaint.

Screencast-O-Matic has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to JAMS, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit JAMs complaint page <https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim> for more information or to file a complaint.  The services of JAMs are provided at no cost to you.

If your Privacy Shield complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See Privacy Shield Annex 1 at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>.
